Aliu Olalekan Ajibade

Front End Developer / Graphic Designer

Phone: +234 808 483 8268

Website: https://olamilekan.netlify.app

Email: aliuajibade317@gmail.com

I am an experienced software engineer and graphic designer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. I am skilled in React Js, Sanity CMS, MySQLi DB, PHP and Adobe Photoshop. I am looking forward to building products that will challenge and test my competence in a way that allows me to contribute effectively while also developing my skills.

EXPERIENCE

Olive Crescent Scholars Limited

Jan 2020 - Dec 2021

Front End Trainer

- taught foundation of web development
- used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule.
- did not only unblock my students when they encounter a bottleneck in a timely fashion, but I also ensure to tell them the reason for the error.

TechEnd Incubation Limited

Oct 2018 - June 2020

Web Development and Graphics Design Intern

I underwent training on web development and graphics and later worked with a UI/UX tutor and some students to build various projects.

- make web designs using Figma under the supervision of the tutor.
- · make graphic designs for ongoing projects.
- · make websites on management request
- mentor surbodinate interns

A handful of Tool was used such as Git, Github, Codepen, PHP, jQuery, React Js, JavaScript, Boostrap, SASS, Adobe Photoshop, to mention a few.

Freelancer Jan 2019 - current

Web Developer, Graphic Designer and Teacher

- taught the latest and in-demand skills in Web development to my students.
- · teach graphics.
- teach Arabic and other Islamic related subjects

Olive Crescent Scholars Limited

Sept 2011 - October 2018

Teacher

• teach Arabic language and other Islamic related subjects

Firm Consulting Limited

August 2015 - August 2018

<u>Audit Trainee</u>

Analyse bank statements and execute other official assignments

Madrasatul Usool-Eeman

April 2010 – December 2011

Teacher

• Teach Arabic language other related Islamic subjects

Nigerian Bottling Company (Coca-Cola)

February 2003 - August 2004

Office Assistant

• Execute official assignment

EDUCATION -

Annahdah Institute of Arabic and Islamic Studies, Alimosho, Lagos.

October 2007 – Till Date

Zad Academy, Makkah, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.

August 2020 - April 2022

Diploma in Islamic Law (Distinction)

International Open University (Formerly Islamic Online University), Gambia.

2018

Diploma in Islamic Studies

Power Excel Academy, Egbeda, Lagos.

University of Lagos, Lagos.

Bachelor of Science in Accounting (CGPA 3.36)

April 2010 - December 2014

State High School Oyewole, Agege, Lagos.

Senior School Certificate Examination

October 1996 – August 2002

Zion African Church Primary School, Alagbaa, Iyana-Ipaja, Agege, Lagos.

1991 - 1996

First School Leaving Certificate

SKILLS

PHP, MySQLi DB, Typescript, JavaScript, Git and Github, Google, Figma design, Bash, and Adobe Photoshop.
HTLM5, CSS3, jQuery, React Js, React-hooks, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI Material-UI, CSS Preprocessor (SASS/SCSS).

Communication, Team-work, Attention to details, Adaptability, Agile Project Management. Tools: Slack, Zoom, Google Meetings, Microsoft Word and Excel.